<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://emiliojd.github.io/blog</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 16:22:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Running with my ancestors]]></title><description><![CDATA[Lately, I’ve been running. Now, I am not a runner by any means but it has become progressively more entertaining as time goes on. Most of my…]]></description><link>https://emiliojd.github.io/blog/running-ancestors/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://emiliojd.github.io/blog/running-ancestors/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I am not a runner by any means but it has become progressively more entertaining as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my motivation stems from generic reasons. Better health. Clears your head. Keeps you slim. The other portion comes from a silent semi-bonding commitment I’ve made to myself that I’ll run the Boston Half-Marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It falls on November 12th, two days before my 23rd birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless if I make it or not, I want to keep running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started running by just jogging for 10-20 minutes a day. Sometimes tracking it, sometimes not. In the past two weeks, I’ve progressed to slightly longer runs. Running is hard. I never understood the sentiment that running is fun, how could something so painful and taxing be fun? But it ends up being the pain and the hardness that makes it enjoyable. It’s about pushing for a while and then zoning out and forgetting that you are in pain. Tapping into that flow state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though sometimes, it’s not a flow state at all. Sometimes, running is about pushing a bit past your limits and convincing yourself that you have more steam than you originally thought. In flying they call this “pushing the envelope.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’m in these moments, where I’m about to slow down and give up, I’ve began practicing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve started imagining someone running next to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a pacer, anything is possible. After all, my first time getting up to 2.5 miles of distance (short, I know, but I was proud of it) was when I was jogging with my girlfriend. When you run with someone else, it reminds you what the human body is capable of. You can dig deeper because you realize other people are feeling the same pain you’re feeling, and they can get over it, so why can’t you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing this written out, it seems a bit toxic. But in real life it’s a bit more wholesome. There is fun in sharing a little pain with someone else. Someone in my public speaking class used a term to describe this phenomena a few months ago - “trauma bonding.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I don’t always have a pacer with me. Luckily, I have my imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think imagination is an innate talent, but a practiced skill. Some might be better at conjuring objects in their mind, but to emulate feeling, raw feeling, that’s just will power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been running with my ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts off small, I’ll think of one person next to me, then they bring in two others, who each bring in two others. This exponential growth of family happens until I am running with a swarm of people. Just me and a herd plowing through the streets of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My family is mostly faceless. Being a descendant of poor people means that I don’t have an abundance of photos or written family history. Yet, I feel like I know them. I know that they lived their lives in a world much different from mine, a life that was much harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that I was faceless to them. They didn’t know who I was, but they worked hard to ensure I can be great. They kept pushing. Running is all about pushing. Continuing to move forward. In the Dominican Republic they refer to tough men as tiburon, or shark. I like thinking of myself as a shark when I run, keep moving forward, or die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people I imagine push me up hills and heal my pain. It started with running but I slowly feel it permeating to every action in my life. All my actions are guided by rich history and sacrifice. I am never alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I try looking up this phenomena online, the first couple of results link to psychosis and hallucination. I guess western medicine hasn’t caught up yet. But this doesn’t stop me from believing. Oh no! I’m sure of it. There is power in the mind. There is power in our blood. Even if my body is all that they have left me with, it is more than enough to summon them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your ancestors are always with you. Even in this very moment. They are helping us up the hill which is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope one day, long after I pass, someone runs with me.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World 2.0]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my first post on my new blog! First off,
it's way too hard to make a blog. You would think something so integral
and simple to the…]]></description><link>https://emiliojd.github.io/blog/hello-world copy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://emiliojd.github.io/blog/hello-world copy/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my new blog! First off,
it&apos;s way too hard to make a blog. You would think something so integral
and simple to the internet would be really quick to spin up.
But, there are actually a couple of steps involved. I guess overall, the steps were
pretty quick. All I did was download a gatsby template and then
host it on GitHub pages. But I don&apos;t know, I expected to do it in a much smoother way.
In fact! I should write a blog post about how to make a free blog as a student.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>